<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Yan&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>https://gzliyan113.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Yan&#39;s Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gzliyan113.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Another Note on A blogdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://gzliyan113.github.io/note/2017/06/14/another-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gzliyan113.github.io/note/2017/06/14/another-note/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered an awesome tutorial on blogdown written by Alison. I have to admit this is the best blogdown tutorial I have seen so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Note on Two Beautiful Websites</title>
      <link>https://gzliyan113.github.io/note/2017/06/13/a-quick-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gzliyan113.github.io/note/2017/06/13/a-quick-note/</guid>
      <description>To me, the two most impressive websites based on blogdown are:
 Rob J Hyndman&amp;rsquo;s personal website. Live Free or Dichotomize by Lucy and Nick et al.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://gzliyan113.github.io/cios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gzliyan113.github.io/cios/</guid>
      <description>Selected CIOS Comments On the course and lectures  &amp;ldquo;Showing how important equations and concepts were derived was one of the best features of the class because helped my understanding of the concepts tremendously.&amp;rdquo;
  &amp;ldquo;The best feature of this course was the lecture.&amp;rdquo;
  &amp;ldquo;The abundance of examples in the lecture notes is really helpful for understanding how specific formulas and concepts can be applied in the real world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry</title>
      <link>https://gzliyan113.github.io/industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gzliyan113.github.io/industry/</guid>
      <description>§ Industry Research I have been fortunate enough to play with some interesting and challenging optimization tasks for training neural recommendation models at an industrial scale. These recommenders, along with their embedding tables, easily exceed trillion bytes in size. Training at this scale creates many interesting stochastic and distributed optimization problems, and calls for usecase-dependent method development.
 Research Intern, Facebook (Meta), Ads Ranking  Date: May 2021 - Nov 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misc</title>
      <link>https://gzliyan113.github.io/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gzliyan113.github.io/misc/</guid>
      <description>§ Outside Research I occasionally lift with optimizers Hongzhang, Chungjae and Kaizhao, unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;m also prone to injury.
I play ok-level badminton, and (barely) entry-level basketball.
I spend most of my time outside research with my wife Hairong, and she has been working on improving healthcare using ML. We have a lovely golden retriever Nomi (糯米).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://gzliyan113.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gzliyan113.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>.custom-list { padding: 0; margin: 0; } .custom-list li { margin-bottom: 8px; /* space between items */ padding-left: 40px; /* Add desired padding value */ list-style-type: none; /* Remove default bullet point */ } .custom-list li::before { content: &#34;•&#34;; /* Add bullet point character */ display: inline-block; width: 10px; /* Adjust bullet point width */ text-align: center; margin-left: -20px; /* Adjust negative margin to remove space */ }  § Research Overview My research focuses on the design and analysis of novel data-driven gradient-based methods to support decision making under uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>https://gzliyan113.github.io/service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gzliyan113.github.io/service/</guid>
      <description>§ Peer Reviewing   Journal:
 IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence Journal of Machine Learning Research Mathematics of Operations Research Mathematical Programming Optimization Letters Operations Research SIAM Journal on Mathamatics of Data Science SIAM Journal on Optimization    Conference:
 International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTAT)    § Sessions &amp;amp; Minisymposiums  International Conference on Continuous Optimization, 2025, Los Angelos International Symposium on Mathematical Programming, 2024, Montreal INFORMS Optimization Society Conference, 2024, Houston INFORMS Annual Meeting, 2023, Phoenix  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://gzliyan113.github.io/talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gzliyan113.github.io/talk/</guid>
      <description>Talks (in reverse chronological order) International Symposium on Mathematical Programming (ISMP)
- July 2024, Montréal - Rectangularity and Duality of Distributionally Robust Markov Decision Processes
Slides
Shanghai Jiao Tong University
- Antai College of Economics and Management - June 2024, Shanghai - Data-driven First-order Methods for Robust Sequential Decision Making
Slides
INFORMS Optimization Society Conference
- March 2024, Houston - Policy Mirror Descent Inherently Explores Action Space
Slides
Texas A&amp;M University</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://gzliyan113.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gzliyan113.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>§ Instructor  ISYE 3770: Statistics and Applications, Spring 2023, Georgia Tech  Introductory probability and statistics course for engineering-majored students. Class size: 69. Teaching evaluation: 4.8/5.0.   Design curriculum, lecture notes, homeworks, and exams. I believe in the essential role of white-board discussion for teaching mathematical content. Kindly find my self-designed syllabus and lecture notes here.    § Teaching Assistant  ISYE 3770: Statistics and Applications, Fall 2018, Spring 2019, Georgia Tech  § Teaching Awards  ISyE Outstanding Graduate Student Instructor Award, 2023, Georgia Tech.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
